Jonathan MacDonald 601 Old Placentia Road Mount Pearl, NL Canada, A1N 3Y5 (709)-368-8788 jhm6121@rit.edu

27 June 2013

Center of Campus Life 1st Floor, 03-1610 Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New York, USA, 14623 (585)-475-4111 crcccl@rit.edu

Hello to whom it may concern,

I am applying for a graduate assistant position with the Center of Campus Life through the off-campus community outreach project.

I have outreach experience through as a resident advisor, a senator with Student Government at Rochester Institute of Technology (RIT), and a my-course administrator with the Department of Access Services at RIT. A copy of my essay is included in the application.

Attached is also a copy of my resume for your convenience.

I look forward to hearing from you.

Sincerely,

Jonathan MacDonald

JONATHAN MACDONALD

601 Old Placentia Road • Mount Pearl • Newfoundland-Labrador • A1N 3Y5 • (709)-368-8788 • jhm6121@rit.edu

EDUCATION

Master of Science Secondary Education for the Deaf

Rochester Institute of Technology (RIT), Rochester, New York

Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science, GPA 3.04/4.0

RIT, Rochester, New York

RESEARCH PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

High Acres Nature Area (HANA)

December 2012 - May 2013

Anticipated May 2015

Environmental Sciences Capstone, RIT, Rochester, New York

• Developed a program to determine conservation priorities for HANA by identifying stakeholders and conducting surveys regarding their suggested conservation targets.

Imagine RIT

Environmental Sciences Field Skills, RIT, Rochester, New York,

May 2012

May 2013

Observed and analyzed water quality data collected from five chosen sites on Allen Creek

Invasive Plant Assessment and Management Plan

Concepts of Environmental Sciences, Liberty Hill, RIT President's Residence - Rochester, NY,

Fall 2011

 Designed a final habitat management plan report detailing the assessment, management activities undertaken, and recommendations for future monitoring and management

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

MyCourses Administrator for RIT Department of Access Services, Rochester, NY

Fall 2012-Present

Responsible for facilitating access services information online

Zookeeper Intern

Fall 2012

Seneca Park Zoo, Rochester, New York

 Assisted with daily duties regarding the care of exotic wildlife ranging from dietary needs to appropriate removal procedures of fecal matter

Orientation Assistant

Summer 2012

RIT New Student Orientation, Rochester, New York

 Responsible for facilitating the transition of a group of approximately 15-18 first year students representing multiple programs from across the University

Research Intern

Summer 2012

Office of Climate Change, Energy Efficiency & Emissions Trading

Government of Newfoundland and Labrador, St. John's, NL

 Collected and merged weather records dating to 1940s in four locations across the province to assess evidence of climate change in terms of precipitation, temperature, and extreme weathers

Cross-Registered Senator

Fall 2011 – Spring 2012

RIT Student Government, Campus Center, Rochester, New York

Participated in all Student Senate and Committees meetings while encouraging community involvement

Resident Advisor

Fall 2010 -- Spring 2012

RIT Center for Residence Life, Rochester, New York

 Implemented and assisted in the daily management of programs in a safe and healthy environment for residents, focusing on developing their health, as well as social and life skills

Statistical-Clerical Support Officer

Summer 2011

Labor Relations Agency, Government of Newfoundland and Labrador, St. John's, NL, Canada

 Researched and supplied statistics online as required by staff, and cataloged statistical informational files, documents, and literature

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT AND VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES

- NTID Committee for Sustainable Practice, Fall 2012-Spring 2013
- Sustainable Practices Committee for Campus, Fall 2012-Spring 2013
- RIT Leadership Institute and Community Service Center, January 2012
- Rochester and the Finger Lakes, New York's Greentopia Festival, September 2011 & 2012
- Royal Canadian Army Cadet Corps 2965, St. John's, Newfoundland, Canada, 2001-2007
- Paychex Leadership Conference, Rochester, NY, February 2012
- Awards NTID Humanitarian Award in Recognition of Empowered and Inspired Students 2011-2012

REFERENCES

Pat Griffin

Former Director of Government Relations
Office of Climate Change, Energy Efficiency &
Emissions Trading
Executive Council
5th Floor, Confed. Blding., West Block
St. John's, NL, A1B 4J6, Canada
(709) 729-1210
patgriffin@gov.nl.ca

Elizabeth DiCesare

Lecturer in the Thomas H. Gosnell School of Life Sciences Rochester Institute of Technology 85 Lomb Memorial Drive Rochester, New York 14623, USA (585)475-5992 ewdsbi@rit.edu

Enid Cardinal

Senior Sustainability Advisor The Office of the President Rochester Institute of Technology Rochester, New York 14623, USA (585) 475-7941 elcpro@rit.edu

John Waud

Lecturer in the Thomas H. Gosnell School of Life Sciences Rochester Institute of Technology 85 Lomb Memorial Drive Rochester, New York 14623, USA jmwscl@rit.edu